Guide to the Yasser Alwan Collection AD.MC.002
Akkasah: Photography Archive (NYU Abu Dhabi)
- Series II: Egypt, 1895-1971 (Box 1-7)
  - A boy standing on the beach with his hands on his hips. 9.5 x 6.5 cm, Undated; cuid520 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    Photographic Prints; Bathing Suits/Swimsuits; Beaches; Boys; Children; Seas; Gelatin Silver Prints; Egypt; Individual Portraits
  - A group lying on blankets at the park (same group as ref550). 7.2 x 10.4 cm, Undated; cuid521 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    Photographic Prints; Parks; Children; Gelatin Silver Prints; Egypt; Picnic; Men; Smoking; Women; Group Portraits; Cigarettes; Clocks/Watches; Outdoors
  - A family group in front of a statue carved in the rocks. 10.8 x 7.2 cm, Undated; cuid522 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    Photographic Prints; Children; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Women; Statues/Sculptures; Men; Gelatin Silver Prints; Egypt; Group Portraits
  - A small group having a picnic at the park (same group as ref448). 10.3 x 7.2 cm, Undated; cuid523 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    Photographic Prints; Group Portraits; Outdoors; Picnic; Toys; Children; Women; Parks; Gelatin Silver Prints; Egypt; Bags/Purses; Cameras
  - A man with three women, standing on a sidewalk. 9.5 x 6.5 cm, Undated; cuid524 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    Gelatin Silver Prints; Egypt; Group Portraits; Photographic Prints; Women; Men; Facial Hair
  - A naked baby on a bed. Same baby from ref553 and ref554. 14.2 x 9.6 cm, Undated; cuid525 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    Boys; Gelatin Silver Prints; Egypt; Individual Portraits; Furnishings; Houses; Photographic Prints; Children
  - A woman with a baby on her lap. Same baby from ref552 and ref554. 14.3 x 9.6 cm, Undated; cuid526 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    Women; Gelatin Silver Prints; Egypt; Children; Boys; Photographic Prints; Furnishings; Houses; Group Portraits
  - A naked baby on the back of a couch. Same baby from ref552 and ref553. 13.8 x 8.7 cm, Undated; cuid527 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    Gelatin Silver Prints; Egypt; Photographic Prints; Furnishings; Children; Boys; Houses; Individual Portraits
  - A baby playing with a bag on the beach, with children behind him in bathing suits. 14.0 x 8.9 cm, Undated; cuid528 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    Gelatin Silver Prints; Egypt; Bags/Purses; Photographic Prints; Bathing Suits/Swimsuits; Beaches; Children; Group Portraits
  - Three men in a car on the side of a road. Text on reverse: Falzaergo Pass, Italy. 6.4 x 10.7 cm, 5 September 1931; cuid537 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    Italian Writing; Mountains/Hills; Cars/Trucks; Men; Photographic Prints; Italy; Gelatin Silver Prints; Group Portraits; Transportation
  - A family group on a beach, with mountains in the background. A small boat is superimposed in the frame. 8.9 x 13.8 cm, Undated; cuid548 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    Buildings; Boats/Ships; Mountains/Hills; Seas; Women; Gelatin Silver Prints; Men; Children; Unknown Locations; Photographic Prints; Group Portraits; Handkerchiefs /Pocket Squares
  - Three people feeding the pigeons in the Piazza St. Marco, in Venice. 14.0 x 9.0 cm, Undated; cuid549 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    Photographic Prints; Smoking; Birds; Venice, Italy; Women; Men; Gelatin Silver Prints; Group Portraits; Buildings; Animals; Handkerchiefs /Pocket Squares; Hats; Cigarettes; Bags/Purses; Facial Hair
  - A studio portrait of a woman wearing athletic shorts and a shirt. 13.9 x 8.8 cm, Undated; cuid550 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    Studio Photography; Gelatin Silver Prints; Jewelry; Clocks/Watches; Photographic Prints; Individual Portraits; Sports; Women; Egypt; Furnishings
  - A family group of women and children on the beach (same group as ref579 and ref580. 8.8 x 13.8 cm, Undated; cuid551 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    Head Covers/Veils; Egypt; Photographic Prints; Buildings; Children; Women; Beaches; Gelatin Silver Prints; Group Portraits; Seas
  - A family group of women and children on the beach (same group as ref578 and ref580). 8.9 x 13.8 cm, Undated; cuid552 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    Group Portraits; Egypt; Beaches; Children; Gelatin Silver Prints; Women; Photographic Prints
  - A family group of women and children on the beach (same group as ref578 and ref579). 8.9 x 13.8 cm, Undated; cuid553 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    Seas; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Buildings; Beaches; Egypt; Children; Women; Group Portraits
  - A woman leaning on a column at the foot of some stairs. 13.9 x 9.0 cm, 7 October 1978; cuid554 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    Cairo, Egypt; Clocks/Watches; Jewelry; Individual Portraits; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Women; Gelatin Silver Prints
  - A portrait of a man and a woman with a child. Arabic text on reverse "Souvenir of Assouan..with my good wishes". 13.5 x 8.8 cm, 13 January 1933; cuid555 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    Fez/Tarboush; Helwan, Egypt; Arabic Writing; Children; Women; Men; Gelatin Silver Prints; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Aswan, Egypt; Group Portraits; Handkerchiefs /Pocket Squares; Furnishings; Hats
  - A studio portrait of a family group. 13.8 x 8.7 cm, Undated; cuid556 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    Photographic Prints; Jewelry; Painted Backdrops; Furnishings; Arabic Writing; Gelatin Silver Prints; Men; Studio Photography; Egypt; Women; Group Portraits; Children; Handkerchiefs /Pocket Squares
  - A woman with black head cover leaning on an upholstered chair. 13.6 x 8.5 cm, Undated; cuid557 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    Studio Photography; Egypt; Photographic Prints; Individual Portraits; Fur Garments; Jewelry; Furnishings; Head Covers/Veils; Gelatin Silver Prints; Women; Painted Backdrops; Bags/Purses
  - A woman sitting in a trellised alcove. 13.7 x 8.6 cm, Undated; cuid558 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    Photographic Prints; Individual Portraits; Alexandria, Egypt; Women; Gelatin Silver Prints; Studio Photography
  - A young woman wearing a white blouse with a frilly collar and two pendant necklaces. 13.9 x 8.6 cm, Undated; cuid559 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    Jewelry; Egypt; Women; Furnishings; Painted Backdrops; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Individual Portraits; Gelatin Silver Prints
  - Two women wearing jewelry. 8.9 x 13.8 cm, Undated; cuid560 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    Gelatin Silver Prints; Egypt; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Jewelry; Women; Group Portraits
  - A man in a suit leaning on a column. Armenian text on reverse: In memory of my beloved sister Yekesean. 13.7 x 8.7 cm, 12 January 1926; cuid561 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    Photographic Prints; Armenian Writing; Gelatin Silver Prints; Egypt; Individual Portraits; Furnishings; Painted Backdrops; Men; Studio Photography; Handkerchiefs /Pocket Squares
  - A group of men and women in front of the Versailles Palace. 8.9 x 14.0 cm, 16 November 1958; cuid562 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    Gelatin Silver Prints; Arabic Writing; Eye Glasses/Sunglasses; Architecture; France; Head Covers/Veils; Hats; Women; Men; Buildings; Group Portraits; Photographic Prints; Palaces; Signatures
  - A man in a suit, resting on a wooden chest. 14.0 x 9.0 cm, Undated; cuid563 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Egypt; Clocks/Watches; Furnishings; Individual Portraits; Men; Painted Backdrops
  - A young woman in a dress with long sleeves on a beach. 13.9 x 8.8 cm, Undated; cuid564 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    Photographic Prints; Bathing Suits/Swimsuits; Beaches; Gelatin Silver Prints; Jewelry; Egypt; Women; Seas; Individual Portraits
  - A young man playing tennis, with a building in the background. 13.8 x 8.8 cm, Undated; cuid565 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    Tennis; Gelatin Silver Prints; Egypt; Photographic Prints; Buildings; Sports; Men; Individual Portraits
  - Men and women playing tennis on the tennis courts (linked ref594). 8.8 x 14.2 cm, Undated; cuid566 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    Photographic Prints; Tennis; Outdoors; Women; Men; Gelatin Silver Prints; Sports; Egypt; Group Portraits
  - Men and women playing tennis (linked ref593) - possibly Gezira Club when it was off limits to Egyptian membership (YA). 8.8 x 14.2 cm, Undated; cuid567 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    Tennis; Gelatin Silver Prints; Outdoors; Cairo, Egypt; Photographic Prints; Sports; Women; Men; Group Portraits
  - A woman in a dark dress. 13.5 x 8.5 cm, 12 April 1949; cuid568 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    Individual Portraits; Arabic Writing; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Flower Garlands/Bouquets; Egypt; Jewelry; Women; Furnishings
  - A man sitting in a beach chair, smoking a cigarette. 14.0 x 9.0 cm, Undated; cuid569 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    Men; Photographic Prints; Arabic Writing; Bathing Suits/Swimsuits; Beaches; Individual Portraits; Gelatin Silver Prints; Egypt; Cigarettes; Smoking; Hats
  - A class of schoolgirls in uniforms. 9.0 x 13.9 cm, Undated; cuid570 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    Photographic Prints; Women; Teachers; Students; Uniforms; Schools/Education; Girls; Gelatin Silver Prints; Egypt; Group Portraits; Boys; Children
  - Three women at a fountain in a garden. 8.4 x 14.0 cm, Undated; cuid571 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    Ponds; Fountains; Group Portraits; Girls; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Gardens; Egypt; Women; Group Portraits
  - A soldier in a military uniform with a mustache. 13.6 x 8.5 cm, Undated; cuid572 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    Uniforms; Military/Soldiers; Facial Hair; Men; Medals/Insignia; Facial Hair; Individual Portraits; Gelatin Silver Prints; Egypt; Photographic Prints
  - A hand-painted portrait of a young man in a suit and tarbouche. 13.6 x 8.6 cm, Undated; cuid573 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Fez/Tarboush; Individual Portraits; Gelatin Silver Prints; Children; Cairo, Egypt; Boys; Hand-colored Photographs/Hand-tinting; Furnishings; Hats
  - A group walking down on a street. 13.4 x 8.2 cm, Undated; cuid574 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    Photographic Prints; Streets/Roads; Eye Glasses/Sunglasses; Men; Boys; Women; Children; Gelatin Silver Prints; Egypt; Group Portraits
  - Men in suits with body builders/wrestlers. 8.8 x 13.7 cm, Undated; cuid575 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    Sports; Men; Photographic Prints; Fez/Tarboush; Group Portraits; Buildings; Gelatin Silver Prints; Egypt; Boys; Children; Handkerchiefs /Pocket Squares; Facial Hair; Hats
  - A woman swimming. 8.9 x 14.0 cm, Undated; cuid576 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Loutraki, Greece; Seas; Egypt; Bathing Suits/Swimsuits; Women; Individual Portraits
  - A negative image of two women with umbrellas standing on the beach in front of a hotel (ΠΗΓΗ ΚΑΡΑΝΤΑΝΗ). 9.0 x 14.0 cm, Undated; cuid577 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    Gelatin Silver Prints; Loutraki, Greece; Architecture; Buildings; Hotels; Greek Writing; Negative Images; Photographic Prints; Umbrellas/Parasols; Beaches; Women; Boats/Ships; Group Portraits; Outdoors
  - Three men walking on a street. 12.9 x 8.6 cm, Undated; cuid578 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    Streets/Roads; Photographic Prints; Fez/Tarboush; Eye Glasses/Sunglasses; Gelatin Silver Prints; Egypt; Men; Group Portraits; Handkerchiefs /Pocket Squares; Facial Hair; Hats
  - A mixed group with a gazelle. 8.8 x 11.1 cm, 17 October 1932; cuid579 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    Gelatin Silver Prints; Egypt; Photographic Prints; Antelopes; Gardens; Children; Group Portraits; Women; Arabic Writing; Men; Animals; Fez/Tarboush; Outdoors; Handkerchiefs /Pocket Squares; Hats
  - Two men playing cards and smoking. 8.4 x 10.8 cm, Undated; cuid580 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    Men; Photographic Prints; Smoking; Cigarettes; Gelatin Silver Prints; Egypt; Card Games; Clocks/Watches; Group Portraits; Handkerchiefs /Pocket Squares
  - A small family group, two people sit in a conversation chair. 13.5 x 8.3 cm, Undated; cuid581 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    Egypt; Painted Backdrops; Gelatin Silver Prints; Studio Photography; Facial Hair; Photographic Prints; Head Covers/Veils; Girls; Facial Hair; Women; Men; Furnishings; Group Portraits; Children; Handkerchiefs /Pocket Squares; Jewelry
  - A school group with three men. 8.9 x 14.0 cm, 1 February 1935; cuid582 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    Children; Mansoura, Egypt; Eye Glasses/Sunglasses; Men; Teachers; Schools/Education; Boys; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Egypt; Fez/Tarboush; Students; Group Portraits; Handkerchiefs /Pocket Squares; Hats
  - A young woman in a dress with shoulder detailing. 13.5 x 8.3 cm, 13 May 1949; cuid583 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    Individual Portraits; Women; Gelatin Silver Prints; Jewelry; Alexandria, Egypt; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Arabic Writing; Furnishings; Clocks/Watches
  - A multi-generational family group. 8.7 x 13.5 cm, 28 July 1944; cuid584 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    Eye Glasses/Sunglasses; Head Covers/Veils; Women; Men; Izmir, Turkey; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Turkish Writing; Arabic Writing; Group Portraits
  - A baby girl with a doll. 8.6 x 13.6 cm, Undated; cuid585 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    Toys; Arabic Writing; Girls; Egypt; Jewelry; Studio Photography; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Children; Individual Portraits; Carpets/Rugs; Carpets/Rugs
  - Three men in suits resting on a car in front of a restaurant. 8.9 x 13.9 cm, 16 May 1937; cuid586 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    Eye Glasses/Sunglasses; Men; Cars/Trucks; Group Portraits; Egypt; Fez/Tarboush; Gelatin Silver Prints; Arabic Writing; Photographic Prints; Restaurants/bars; Transportation; Hats
  - A boat off of Rhoda Island, Cairo, Egypt. 9.1 x 12.1 cm, March 1944; cuid587 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    Photographic Prints; Outdoors; Arabic Writing; Nile River; Boats/Ships; Cairo, Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints
  - A family group of men in a garden (same family from ref617 and 618). 14.0 x 9.0 cm, Undated; cuid588 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    Boys; Men; Constantinople; Istanbul, Turkey; Photographic Prints; Gardens; Cigarettes; Gelatin Silver Prints; Smoking; Children; Group Portraits; Facial Hair
  - A portrait of a man, woman, and boy seated in the grass (same group from ref616 and ref618). 14.0 x 9.0 cm, Undated; cuid589 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    Photographic Prints; Constantinople; Gardens; Boys; Women; Men; Gelatin Silver Prints; Children; Group Portraits; Facial Hair
  - A multi-generational group in a park (same family as ref616 and ref617). 9.0 x 14.0 cm, Undated; cuid590 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    Photographic Prints; Gardens; Head Covers/Veils; Children; Women; Men; Gelatin Silver Prints; Boys; Constantinople; Group Portraits; Facial Hair
  - A man in double-breasted suit looking off camera. 13.8 x 8.7 cm, Undated; cuid591 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    Men; Painted Backdrops; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Egypt; Individual Portraits; Gelatin Silver Prints; Facial Hair
  - Two women wearing detailed dresses and handbags. 13.5 x 8.4 cm, Undated; cuid592 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    Gelatin Silver Prints; Painted Backdrops; Bags/Purses; Egypt; Jewelry; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Women; Group Portraits; Furnishings; Head Covers/Veils
  - A Fallahi, holding an umbrella. 11.9 x 8.9 cm, Undated; cuid593 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    Gelatin Silver Prints; Regional/National Dress; Men; Photographic Prints; Egypt; Umbrellas/Parasols; Individual Portraits; Facial Hair
  - A baby on a swing. 9.0 x 13.9 cm, Undated; cuid594 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Parks; Children; Egypt; Individual Portraits
  - Three men stand around a table, one holds a pen to paper. 8.9 x 14.0 cm, Undated; cuid595 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    Group Portraits; Signatures; Pens/Inkwells; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Alexandria, Egypt; Men; Facial Hair
  - A group sit at a table next to a beach. 8.5 x 13.6 cm, 1967; cuid596 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    Head Covers/Veils; Armenian Writing; Bathing Suits/Swimsuits; Beaches; Photographic Prints; Signatures; Gelatin Silver Prints; Abu Qir, Egypt; Women; Men; Cigarettes; Group Portraits; Facial Hair
  - Two women, one in fur coat, and a man wearing a bow tie. 13.8 x 8.6 cm, Undated; cuid597 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Fur Garments; Women; Group Portraits; Men; Bow Ties; Egypt
  - A woman in a black dress leaning on chair. 13.8 x 8.9 cm, Undated; cuid598 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Pianos; Books; Jewelry; Painted Backdrops; Women; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Individual Portraits; Furnishings
  - A bride with large flower bouquet with a floor length veil. 13.9 x 8.8 cm, Undated; cuid599; S. Zoulis, Cairo (Egypt) (Box 3, Folder 20)
    Painted Backdrops; Photographic Prints; Jewelry; Gloves; Flower Garlands/Bouquets; Gelatin Silver Prints; Women; Weddings; Individual Portraits; Women; Studio Photography; Weddings; Cairo, Egypt
  - A group gathered around a table covered with bread rolls. 9.0 x 14.0 cm, Undated; cuid600 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    Egypt; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Parties; Houses; Eye Glasses/Sunglasses; Women; Food; Men; Group Portraits; Drinks/Beverages; Food; Furnishings; Handkerchiefs /Pocket Squares
  - Two young men in matching jackets and white clothes. Dores, Alexandria, Egypt. 13.0 x 8.1 cm, Undated; cuid601 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    Children; Studio Photography; Boys; Alexandria, Egypt; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Group Portraits
  - A man with a mustache wearing a collared shirt. 13.5 x 8.3 cm, 17 December 1956; cuid602 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    Alexandria, Egypt; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Men; Facial Hair; Gelatin Silver Prints; Individual Portraits; Facial Hair; Arabic Writing
  - A child seated on an animal headed bench. 13.7 x 8.8 cm, 17 October 1936; cuid603 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    Children; Furnishings; Alexandria, Egypt; Studio Photography; Painted Backdrops; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Individual Portraits
  - Two Greek men in suits, smoking cigarettes in a park. 9.0 x 14.0 cm, 21 May 1933; cuid604 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    Signatures; Egypt; Greek Writing; Parks; Smoking; Cigarettes; Gelatin Silver Prints; Men; Photographic Prints; Group Portraits; Handkerchiefs /Pocket Squares; Facial Hair
  - A group wedding portrait. 8.7 x 13.1 cm, Undated; cuid605 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    Photographic Prints; Flower Garlands/Bouquets; Alexandria, Egypt; Women; Gelatin Silver Prints; Weddings; Men; Head Covers/Veils; Facial Hair; Handkerchiefs /Pocket Squares; Group Portraits; Jewelry
  - A view of a restaurant with staff. 9.0 x 14.3 cm, Undated; cuid606 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    Cairo, Egypt; Men; Photographic Prints; Waiting staff/Servers; Furnishings; Restaurants/bars; Uniforms; Gelatin Silver Prints; Group Portraits; Workers
  - Chefs and kitchen staff and waiters. 9.0 x 14.0 cm, Undated; cuid607 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    Waiting staff/Servers; Photographic Prints; Cairo, Egypt; Uniforms; Men; Restaurants/bars; Gelatin Silver Prints; Group Portraits; Chefs/Cooks; Facial Hair; Workers
  - Four children pose with various props against a painted backdrop. 8.6 x 13.6 cm, Undated; cuid608 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    Gelatin Silver Prints; Egypt; Statues/Sculptures; Books; Furnishings; Studio Photography; Painted Backdrops; Children; Photographic Prints; Group Portraits; Girls; Boys; Carpets/Rugs
  - Two men in military uniform. 12.0 x 8.8 cm, 29 July 1938; cuid609 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Egypt; Greek Writing; Military/Soldiers; Uniforms; Men; Group Portraits
  - A seated woman with two girls wearing black bows in their hair 13.7 x 8.7 cm, Undated; cuid610 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    Armenian Writing; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Bags/Purses; Painted Backdrops; Women; Girls; Alexandria, Egypt; Studio Photography; Children; Group Portraits; Furnishings
  - Two men in suits and a woman in a bathing suit pose on a boat. 8.9 x 13.8 cm, 3 July 1931; cuid611 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    Boats/Ships; Cesme, Izmir, Turkey; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Beaches; Women; Seas; Bathing Suits/Swimsuits; Turkish Writing; Group Portraits; Facial Hair; Men; Transportation; Coast
  - Two seated women with a standing man in a sailor's uniform. 13.7 x 8.6 cm, Undated; cuid612 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    Military/Soldiers; Uniforms; Gelatin Silver Prints; Egypt; Photographic Prints; Men; Navy; Women; Group Portraits; Carpets/Rugs
  - Two men in suits. 13.6 x 8.6 cm, Undated; cuid613 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    Men; Izmir, Turkey; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Gelatin Silver Prints; Handkerchiefs /Pocket Squares; Group Portraits
  - Two women seated on a bench. 13.9 x 8.7 cm, Undated; cuid614 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    Clocks/Watches; Furnishings; Jewelry; Studio Photography; Gelatin Silver Prints; Egypt; Painted Backdrops; Photographic Prints; Women; Group Portraits; Carpets/Rugs
  - A group of three men and two women swimming in a pool. 9.4 x 14.3 cm, Undated; cuid615 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    Gelatin Silver Prints; Egypt; Photographic Prints; Women; Men; Swimming; Swimming Pools; Group Portraits; Facial Hair
  - A woman seated in a wicker chair outdoors in front of a stone building. 13.9 x 8.9 cm, Undated; cuid616 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    Furnishings; Women; Gelatin Silver Prints; Egypt; Photographic Prints; Individual Portraits
  - A negative image of four women sitting at a cafe. 9.1 x 13.9 cm, Undated; cuid617 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    Group Portraits; Photographic Prints; Fur Garments; Drinks/Beverages; Restaurants/bars; Women; Negative Images; Gelatin Silver Prints; Egypt
  - A woman wearing a dark outfit with a white collar and white gloves. 13.9 x 8.9 cm, Undated; cuid618 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    Individual Portraits; Photographic Prints; Painted Backdrops; Gloves; Bags/Purses; Studio Photography; Head Covers/Veils; Women; Gelatin Silver Prints; Egypt; Furnishings
  - A multi-generational group pose in front of a building. 8.9 x 13.9 cm, Undated; cuid619 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    Photographic Prints; Buildings; Fez/Tarboush; Gelatin Silver Prints; Egypt; Clocks/Watches; Children; Women; Men; Group Portraits; Facial Hair; Hats
  - A portrait of a man and a woman standing in doorway, the man wearing a tarbouche and glasses holds the woman's face, possibly from a film. 13.9 x 8.9 cm, Undated; cuid620 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    Photographic Prints; Films; Women; Men; Eye Glasses/Sunglasses; Gelatin Silver Prints; Egypt; Fez/Tarboush; Group Portraits; Hats
  - A hand-painted portrait of a woman wearing a blue jacket. 13.3 x 8.4 cm, Undated; cuid621 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    Women; Studio Photography; Individual Portraits; Photographic Prints; Hand-colored Photographs/Hand-tinting; Gelatin Silver Prints; Egypt; Jewelry
  - A woman wearing an outfit with a lace collar, looking off camera. 13.5 x 8.6 cm, Undated; cuid622 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    Women; Individual Portraits; Photographic Prints; Jewelry; Heliopolis, Cairo, Egypt; Studio Photography; Gelatin Silver Prints
  - A young man in a suit with a book on his lap. M. Sheredan. 13.5 x 8.6 cm, Undated; cuid623 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    Lancashire, England, UK; English Writing; England, UK; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Books; Individual Portraits; Men; Gelatin Silver Prints; Furnishings
  - A studio portrait of a a man and a woman wearing a dress with a patterned collar. 13.7 x 8.6 cm, Undated; cuid624 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    Gelatin Silver Prints; Jewelry; Facial Hair; Photographic Prints; Women; Men; Fez/Tarboush; Studio Photography; Egypt; Facial Hair; Group Portraits; Furnishings; Hats
  - Women and children gathered around a fountain, filling a jug with water. 14.0 x 8.9 cm, Undated; cuid625 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    Women; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Fountains; Children; Egypt; Group Portraits
  - A group sitting in a boat (linked ref655). 8.7 x 13.9 cm, Undated; cuid626 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    Egypt; Women; Children; Gelatin Silver Prints; Boats/Ships; Photographic Prints; Nile River; Girls; Group Portraits
  - Two women from ref654 standing on the stairs of a porch in front of a house. 13.9 x 8.8 cm, Undated; cuid627 (Box 3, Folder 23)